Suraj Hande

Senior Software Engineer

surajhande@hotmail.com

+91 - 9700017285

Hyderabad, India

surajhande_1

Summary

A Software Engineer with 4+ years of professional experience developing customer-facing software. Ability to contribute at all levels of the software development life cycle.

Skills & Competencies

Android SDK: 4+ years of experience with applications published in Google Play Store.

Oracle Certified Java Programmer (OCJP).

Experience programming with Kotlin.

3+ years of programming in C++.

Strong with general data structures and algorithms.

Knowledge of architectural patterns like MVP and MVVM.

Knowledge of Material Design guidelines.

Hands-on with Android Jetpack components and libraries like Retrofit, Glide etc.

Experience working with REST and JSON.

Unit testing with JUnit, Espresso etc.

Hands-on with version control systems like Git and SVN.

Work Experience

Polycom (NYSE: PLT)

Hyderabad

Senior Software Engineer

September 2016 - Ongoing

Software/Android Framework Developer at Polycom voice endpoints team, responsible for developing and integrating UC software features for new and existing products. I work in an agile environment developing software features in scrum sprints.

Responsibilities:

Developing software for VoIP phones ensuring fast and reliable. performance. Actively participate in the product development phase. Take ownership of modules and provide ways to improve customer experience.

Tools & Frameworks used:

AOSP, Android SDK, Java, C++, Qt, Git, SVN

Intern

December 2015 - August 2016

Software Intern for the Polycom voice product team. I was responsible for developing tools and plugins to help with monitoring and debugging network issues for their upcoming VoIP devices.

Tools & Frameworks used:

C, C++, TCP/UDP, Wireshark

Education

Computer Science and Engineering

Bachelor of Technology from August 2012 to June 2016

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University.

LInks

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/surajhander/

GitHub: https://github.com/srjhnd
Portfolio: https://srjhnd.github.io/
PlayStore: http://tiny.cc/tkwviz